Paper (Ken-Jung) Lee

paper.li@gmail.com https://paperworkstud.io +17472039925

Brief

UX DESIGN | PROTOTYPING | APPS | AR/VR

Paper Lee is an experienced designer with 10+ years of UI/UX design experience for mobile apps, websites, and VR/AR projects. He owns plural AR apps (Gallery AR, Fascroll, and MoCáp) in the App Store to explore the unique use cases with AR technology. He helped Diing ship its flagship VRTube in Oculus Go and multiple VR medical training programs for HTC and medical centers in Taiwan. Paper Lee devoted his early career to various mobile app and website projects. His strengths in interactive prototyping and UI/UX design motivate him to learn new stuff continuously. His proficiency in many prototyping tools, such as Xcode, Unity, Framer, Sketch, etc., ensures that he can make prototypes rapidly and frequently during the design process.

Experience

PRODUCT DESIGNER

VOLLEY, SAN FRANCISCO, MAR. 2022 - NOW

UI and UX design for voice games and applications in smart speakers and smart TVs, i.e., Echo Show devices, FireTV, Roku, etc. Wireframes, voice and visual flows, prototyping, and high-fidelity visual designs.

LEAD PRODUCT DESIGNER

DIING, TAIPEI / LOS ANGELES, JUN. 2016 - FEB. 2022

Define product scope, interaction, and UX landscape for mobile apps, VR/AR applications, and websites among education, entertainment, Al, and IoT. Product strategy, user research, interaction design, prototyping, visual design, UI design, technical assessment, and team leading.

SENIOR PRODUCT DESIGNER

UNIGREEN, TAIPEI, AUG. 2015 - MAY 2016

Define product scope, interaction, and UX landscape for agriculture products apps. Product strategy, principle design, user research, visual design, UI design, interaction design, prototyping, and team leading.

SENIOR USER INTERFACE DESIGNER

MOBIAPPS, TAIPEI, DEC. 2012 - JUL. 2015

UI/UX design for mobile apps and websites among royalty programs, chat apps, and e-commerce. Product strategy, user research, principle design, UI design, prototyping, visual design, usability assessment, Website design & development.

USER INTERACTION DESIGNER

PILOTFISH, MUNICH, AUG. 2011 - AUG. 2012

Design research, brainstorming, ideation, user interface design, graphic design, and prototyping.

USABILITY ENGINEER

KATDC, TAIPEI, SEP. 2008 - JUN. 2011

In-house Usability lab build-up, prototyping, usability assessments, design system definition, and project leading for TV set-top boxes.

MECHANICAL ENGINEER CTCI, TAIPEI, MAR. 2008 - AUG. 2008

Design the static equipment used in the chemical planet, such as pressure vessels, towers, tanks, etc. Technologic spec inspection of equipment quotation from worldwide vendors.

Education

M.S., BIOMEDICAL ENGINEERING

NATIONAL YANG-MING UNIVERSITY, TAIPEI, 2005 - 2007

"3D Dynamic Model Construction for Predicting Knee Kinematics - Comparison of native knee and knee arthroplasty", presented on the 21th Congress of International Society of Biomechanics

"Three-dimensional Dynamic Model Construction for Predicting Knee Kinematics - Comparison of Native Knee and Knee Arthroplasty", Masters thesis

B.S., MECHANICAL AND ELECTRO-MECHANICAL ENGINEERING NATIONAL SUN YAT-SEN UNIVERSITY, KAOHSIUNG, 2001 - 2005

"Man back-supporting system - A best supporting points analysis", presented on the 21th National Conference on Mechanical Engineering of CSME

Skills

Tool

Sketch, Framer, Affinity Photo/Designer/Publisher, Blender, Figma, Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, Indesign, Adobe After Effects, Lottie Animation, InVision, Marvel

HTML/CSS/JavaScript, Jekyll, React, Swift, iOS development, Android development

Unity, Xcode, Android Studio, Lens Studio, Spark AR Studio, Oculus, SteamVR, Marquette

User Experience Design

Prototyping, mobile app design, web design, UI design, UX design, AR design, VR design, interaction design, visual design, User Centered Design

Language

Mandarine, English, German

Portfolio

paperworkStudio

https://paperworkstud.io